mymerchantoffice.com 2015-03-16

# Business Track Online Privacy & Cookies Statement

Business Track Online Privacy & Cookies Statement
Effective January 1, 2014
First Data Merchant Services Corporation is a subsidiary of First Data Corporation
Protecting the privacy of users of Business Track is important to us. Our Online Privacy &
Cookies Statement is designed to inform you about our collection and use of personal information
on this website. From time to time, First Data Merchant Services Corporation (referred to in this
policy as FDMS) may make changes to this Online Privacy & Cookies Statement so we
encourage you to check back and review it regularly to ensure you are aware of current practices.
The Online Privacy & Cookies Statement is available on the home page of this website and
throughout the website where you provide us with personal information.
If you have any questions, please contact                   the   First   Data   Privacy  Office at
dataprivacyoffice@firstdata.com or (888) 337-0434.
The Personal Information We Collect Through This Site is the Personal Information You
Provide to Us.
The personal information we collect about you on this website is the information that you provide
to us. This information may include, for example, name, mailing address, email address, phone
number and similar information. In some cases you may provide it directly, such as by entering
information into an application or online form, and in some cases you may provide it indirectly,
such as the IP address of the computer or device you use to connect with us online. We may
use the personal information you provide us to:
         provide you with the information you have requested,
         facilitate and complete merchant-initiated or authorized transactions,
         provide analytics and other value-added services,
         comply with federal, state and local laws, including credit reporting laws and card
          association rules,
         verify information and combat fraud, or
         occasionally send you other information about First Data and its services that we believe
          you would find interesting.
When You Browse the First Data Website, We Do Not Seek to Determine Your Identity.
Personal information, such as your email address, is not included in cookies and is not collected
unless you provide it to us. FDMS does not disclose domain name or aggregate information to
third parties other than vendors who assist us with our website and who are under contractual
confidentiality requirements.
From time to time, however, we may disclose this information to fulfill legal or regulatory
obligations or if we determine such disclosure is legally advisable or necessary to protect our
rights, the rights of others, or to prevent harm (for example, for fraud prevention purposes we may
confirm that your IP address matches the location you enter into an online form). In addition, we
may aggregate data about users of our site and use it for statistical or analytic purposes. This
information helps us to better understand our site’s users and how to improve our site and our
offerings.

Information about Online Tracking
Some browsers incorporate a Do Not Track feature that signals to websites you visit that you do
not want to have your online activity tracked. Tracking is not the same as using or collecting
information in connection with a single website. For these purposes tracking refers to collecting
personally identifiable information from consumers who use or visit a website or online service as
they move across different websites over time.
How browsers communicate the Do Not Track signal is not yet uniform. As a result this site is not
yet set up to interpret or respond to Do Not Track signals communicated by your browser. Even
so, as described more fully throughout this Online Privacy Statement, we limit our use and
collection of your personal information.
For a description of Do Not Track protocols for browsers and mobile devices, or simply to learn
more about the choices available to you, you can visit the All About Do Not Track website:
http://allaboutdnt.com.
Use of Cookies on this Website
This web site may use cookies solely to aggregate information about the pages that users visit so
that we can update and redesign, as necessary, our web site in order to provide you with the
most useful information.
A cookie is a small file, typically of letters and numbers, downloaded on to a device such as a
computer when a user accesses certain websites. Cookies allow a website to recognize a user’s
device.
Cookies can expire at the end of a browser session (from when a user opens the browser window
to when they exit the browser) or they can be stored for longer.
Session cookies – allow websites to link the actions of a user during a browser session. They
may be used for a variety of purposes such as remembering what a user has put in their
shopping basket as they browse around a site. They could also be used for security or to facilitate
use of webmail. These session cookies expire after a browser session so would not be stored
longer term.
Persistent cookies – are stored on a users’ device in between browser sessions which allows
the preferences or actions of the user across a site (or in some cases across different websites)
to be remembered. Persistent cookies may be used for a variety of purposes including
remembering users’ preferences and choices when using a site or to target advertising.
First and third party cookies – Whether a cookie is ‘first’ or ‘third’ party refers to the website or
domain placing the cookie. First party cookies in basic terms are cookies set by a website visited
by the user - the website displayed in the URL window. Third party cookies are cookies that are
set by a domain other than the one being visited by the user. If a user visits a website and a
separate company sets a cookie through that website this would be a third party cookie.
For more information about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to
manage, block and delete them, see: http://www.allaboutcookies.org/.
This website uses the following cookies. You can delete, remove your consent and/or block
cookies sent to you from this website but parts of the website may not then work.
To opt out of being tracked by                   Google  Analytics    across    all   websites   visit
http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout.

Cookie Name                            Cookie Purpose                     More Information
IV_JCT=%2FportalL                      Without this cookie, there are     None applicable
                                       some areas within the website
                                       that    will   not     function
                                       properly. There is no personal
                                       information stored in this
                                       cookie.
Username=value                         Without this cookie, there are     None applicable
                                       some areas within the website
                                       that    will   not     function
                                       properly. There is no personal
                                       information stored in this
                                       cookie.
We Are Committed to Protecting the Confidentiality of User Information.
Our policies limit access to personal user information that is collected from this website to our
employees and agents and the employees and/or agents of our affiliates and business partners
who need the information to fulfill their business responsibilities. FDMS may disclose personal
information collected online to our affiliates and to vendors who assist us with the website. In
some cases, this may require your information to be sent to other countries. By supplying your
information on this website, you consent to your information being transferred across national
borders to FDMS and its affiliates, vendors or agents. Vendors and other outside contractors we
engage are subject to our contractual requirements for safeguarding personal information.
Employees and others with duties related to this website must adhere to this Online Privacy &
Cookies Statement. Our employees receive annual training about the privacy policies and
procedures of First Data Corporation and its affiliates and subsidiaries.            We appreciate that
protecting consumer privacy is a key part of our trusted relationship with our clients.
Any employee violating this Online Privacy & Cookies Statement may be subject to disciplinary
action, up to and including dismissal.
By using this website, you agree that your use of Business Track is limited to the terms stated in
any applicable agreement you have with your Processor.
We Use Appropriate Security Safeguards.
At FDMS, security is a priority. FDMS employs appropriate measures, including advanced
technology, to protect personal information collected online against unauthorized access,
disclosure, alteration or destruction. These measures may include, among others, encryption,
physical access security, and other appropriate technologies. FDMS reviews and enhances its
security systems as necessary.
This Website is Not Directed at Persons Under the Age of 18.
Our website is not directed at or intended for persons under the age of 18 and FDMS does not
knowingly collect or maintain information at our web site from persons under the age of 18.
This Website May Be Linked to Other Websites.
As you navigate our site, you may click to websites of our affiliated companies or business
partners. Those web sites may have their own online privacy statements or policies. This Online
Privacy & Cookies Statement will not apply when you move to one of these other sites because
affiliate privacy practices and policies are tailored to the products and services offered by the
individual affiliate. If you visit the pages and sites of our affiliated business units please be sure to
review the privacy policies applicable to those sites.

We may create links to third-party websites. Neither First Data nor FDMS is responsible for the
privacy practices employed by any third-party websites. First Data and FDMS’s privacy policies
and practices do not apply to these sites. First Data and FDMS do not guarantee, approve, or
endorse any information, material, services, or products contained on or available through any
linked websites. First Data and FDMS are not responsible for any content on sites linked from or
to Business Track. First Data and FDMS are providing links to those sites as a convenience and
your connection to and use of any linked site are at your own risk.
This Online Privacy & Cookies Statement applies only to the information we collect on Business
Track. This Online Privacy & Cookies Statement does not apply to information we collect through
other methods or sources, including sites owned or operated by our affiliates, vendors or
partners.
